Gilberto Ramirez | Software Engineer



gramirez.softwareengineer@gmail.com | 🐨 github.com/Gilberto-Felipe | 💇 LinkedIn: gilbertoramirez-swe





Skills

I'm a Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Fullstack positions, two of them with C# .NET Core, React, SQL. I have experience in the development of Content Management Systems and ERP applications. I have put my hands on C# Rest API development with .NET background. Open to working remotely or being relocated.

C#, .NET Core, Entity Framework, SQL Server, MYSQL, JavaScript, React, .NET Services (Web APIs), Python, PHP, GIT, TFS

Experience

DPR Construction, Remote - Full Stack Engineer

January 2021 - present

- Participated actively in the Software Development Life Cycle in 4 projects.
- Developed and maintained 4 web API applications using C#, .NET Core, Entity Framework, and SQL Server.
- Used Entity Framework Database First approach.
- Integrated, maintained, and documented Web API (.NET Services) to third-party applications.
- Coordinated the migration of 409 jobs from different technologies to the scheduler ActiveBatch.
- Mentored two colleagues to introduce them to projects in both React and .NET Core Web APIs.
- Developed and maintained UI components with JavaScript, React, Material UI, Reactstrap, PrimeReact, Formik, Yup.

GHAPPS, Colima, Mexico - Full Stack Developer Intern

January 2019 - March 2020

- Developed a Content Management System. It provides content for Loro Fan, the mobile app of the University of Colima soccer team.
- Developed the database, the login, UI views, and the backend with PHP and MYSQL using MVC pattern with PHP.

Education

University of Colima, Colima, Mexico - Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering

August 2017 - August 2021

Python for everybody, Coursera online - Specialization Certificate

August 2020

C# Courses, Plural Sight online - Completion certificate

May 2021 - September 2021

C# Fundamentals, Beginning C# Collections, Building an API with ASP.NET Core